Inventory of the John Marshall Papers 1771-1959
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Prints, Engravings, and Artifacts, 1825-1937., 8 items. (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Color lithographs of two portraits of John Marshall., 2 items. Lithographs. Color. (Box-folder 5:4)
    The smaller one was copied from French painter Levret Saint Memin's 1801 crayon portrait of Marshall. The larger lithograph was copied from Chester Harding's 1830 painting.
    Including a copy of and etching of John Marshall's house in Richmond.
  - Black and white facsimiles of silhouettes of John Marshall., 2 items. Facsmilies. Black and White. (Box-folder 5:4)
    The original of the one of Marshall facing right was made in Richmond about 1825 by a French artist. It was hung at Oak Hill, was inherited by his eldest son Thomas Marshall, and is privately owned.
  - Black and white engravings of John Marshall., 3 items. Engravings. Black and White. (Box-folder 5:4)
    Each was copied from the 1801 portrait of Marshall painted by Saint Memin. The large matted one was engraved by J. H. E. Whitney.
  - Black and white photographic print of the 1831 oil painting of Marshall by Henry Inman., 1 item. Photographic Print. Black and White. (Box-folder 5:4)
    Original hangs in the
  - Black and white etchings and engravings of John Marshall., 4 items. Etchings and Engravings. Black and White. (Box-folder 5:4)
    Two obviously derived from Henry Inman's 1831 portrait; one engraved by J. A. O'Neil shows Marshall in 1793 as the Grand Master of the Grand Lodge of Virginia Freemasons; the last includes engravings of portraits of other U.S. Chief Justices: John Jay, Oliver Ellsworth, John Rutledge, R. B. Taney, M. R. Waite, Salmon P. Chase, and Melville W. Fuller.
  - Calendar consisting of several block prints depicting John Marshall's chief decisions, his portrait, and the houses in which he lived, 1937., 7 items. Prints. (Box-folder 5:4)
    Including a short history of Federal Hardware and Implement Mutual Insurance companies.
  - Wooden letter opener, 7 inches long, bearing the words "John Marshall House.", Wood. 7" (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Gold pocket watch probably made by Liverpool watchmaker Robert Roskell and belonging to U.S. Chief Justice John Marshall, [ca. 1799-1825]. (Box-folder 5:4)
  Series 4: Manuscript Volumes
- Manuscript Volumes 1780-1795, n.d. (Box 5-8)
  - Political scrapbook composed by Frank G. Ruffin for the benefit of Governor William E. Cameron, March 1884., 19 pages. MsV. (Box-folder 5:5)
    It consists of a 26 February 1884 memorial to the General Assembly of Virginia, a 25 February letter to the Editor of The State, and handwritten commentary. Ruffin states the reasons why he is opposed to passage of the Richmond Dock and Dry dock bill.
  - Ledger of James Markham Marshall, including his account with his brother, John Marshall, and surveyor's notes made from 1870-1885 in an unknown hand, [1794-1809]., 252 pages. MsV. (Box 6)
  - A transcription of law notes, pages 1-253, from John Marshall's Accounts and Law Notes, 1780. (Box 7)
  - A transcription of pages 1-423 of journal of personal business accounts kept by John Marshall, 1783-1795., 423 pages. Cy MsV. (Box 7)
  - Presentation folder for letters of John Marshall to his wife, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Leaves of account book of John Marshall's which were used as padding beneath the covers of his Accounts and Law Notes, [1776]., 80 pages. MsV. (Box 8)
    This account book has been microfilmed. See Marshall, John M-104. 1 reel of negative microfilm.
  - Journal of personal business accounts kept by John Marshall; also bound with them is a commonplace book of different legal authorities made while Marshall was a student at the College of William and Mary in the Spring of 1780, 1783-1795., 423 pages. MsV. (Box 8)
    This journal of accounts and law notes has been microfilmed. See M-105, M-105a, and M-105b for 3 copies of positive microfilm. See M-l05c for 1 reel of negative microfilm.
  - Jounal in Paris, 17 September 1797 - 11 April 1798. (Othertype M-106)
    Original is located in the Pickering Papers,
    This journal is available only on microfilm. See Marshall, John M-107. 1 reel of negative microfilm.
    Reprint is avilable in The Papers of John Marshall, 1796-1798 (vol. 3); edited by Herbert A. Johnson, Charles T. Cullen, Nancy G. Harris, Charles F. Hobson, et. al.
    Call Number: E302 .M365 v.1 - v.10
- Charcoal sketch of John Marshall after a painting by Henry Inman.